Cesar Hernan Martinez Auguilla

10335 Quillback St, New Market, MD 21774

Phone: 301 693 2976 (Cellular) E-mail: chernanma@msn.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/cesar-martinez-3986b3120/ | GitHub: https://github.com/chernanma

Portfolio: https://chernanma.github.io/Portfolio/

Full Stack Web Developer and Information System Engineer

Full Stack Web Developer with a certificate in Web Development from John Hopkins University passionate about developing meaningful mobile and web apps, using different technologies like CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node.js, Apex, MySQL, etc. Known as an innovator, able to solve complex problems, and team collaborator makes me able to drive feasible outcomes under pressure and develop lifeenhancing user experiences as well as provide the best perspectives on the user experiences with software platforms.

Technical Skills

- **Development environment software:** Microsoft Visual, Microsoft Visual Basic, Studio, Eclipse IDE.
- Database management system software: Oracle PL/SQL, DML.
- Database user interface and query software: Microsoft Access, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle software, Salesforce.
- Web platform development software: AJAX, Apache Tomcat, JavaScript,PHP.
- Object or component oriented development software: C++, jQuery, Microsoft Visual Basic.NET, APEX.

Projects

Covid-10 Test Sites and Stats

GitHub: https://github.com/chernanma/Project_1 | Deployed Project: https://chernanma.github.io/Project_1/

This Covid tracker application delivers the current covid19 updates and statistics nationwide. The User can search for any city and view instantaneous status and trends pertaining to the Coronavirus disease.

In charge of the complete back end development to gather all data from third party APIs and display the most accurate date search by final user.

Technologies

- Html
- jQuery
- Visual Studio Code
- Materialized Framework
- APIs
 - COVID-19 Testing Sites Location API https://developer.here.com/blog/finding-covid-19testing-sites
 - o Google Maps API https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/embed
 - o Google Places API https://maps.googleapis.com/maps/api/place/autocomplete/json?
 - o COVID-19 Information and Stats API https://api.covid19tracking.narrativa.com/api/

Professional Experience

Implementation Manager 2019-Present

HealthWell Foundation, Maryland -USA, www.HealthWellFoundation.org

- Provide redundancy across all areas of the operations process and assists in driving projects to completion while ensuring outcomes align with expectations of the Foundation
- Responsible for day-to-day monitoring of various fund elements and the efficient management of Foundation funds
- Performs process adjustments in the Grants Management System (GMS) related to the status and management of funds

IT Manager, Persiano Rug Inc, 2016-2019

- Hired by Persiano to design and implement a full IT system solution for the company.
- Implemented database system to manage furniture inventory for three branches.
- Server, network, website and social media administration
- I am responsible of the complete modernization of the company.
- Web site: http://www.persianogallery.com/

President, Co-Owner of Msportswear Ltd, Cuenca - Ecuador 2012-present

- Created family owned company while studying for Master's degree
- Manage projects for IT systems and manufacturing processes using the latest technologies
- Oversee production of high-quality competition clothing for high-endurance athletes
- Income and production grew 300% between 2012 and 2013, and 100% from 2015 to 2016
- Web site: http://www.martinezsportswear.com/

Systems Engineer - EXPOCOE, Cuenca - Ecuador

- Hosting and Network administrator
- Website developer and administrator Increased the company's imports and attracted new customers with website and social media enhancements.

Systems Engineer - "La Portada", Cuenca - Ecuador

- Hosting and Network administrator
- Website developer and administrator –attracted new customers with website and social media enhancements.

Systems Engineer – Khalida SPA, Cuenca - Ecuador

- Hosting and Network administrator
- Website developer and administrator –attracted new customers with website and social media enhancements.

Education and Experience

John Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD

Bootcamp Certificate, A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS

University of Azuay, Cuenca – Ecuador

Masters Candidate, May 2014, Geographic Information Systems with emphasis on Land Planning

- Completed Master's curriculum
- Thesis defense planned for December , 2018

GIS Knowledge/Experience

- Spatial reference systems and Global satellite navigation systems
- Aerial Photographs and Photo restoration
- Geodatabases and network analysis
- Satellite Teledetection and Teledetection Sensors
- Temporal Analysis of Teledetection Output
- Exploratory Analysis of Spatial Data and Infrastructure for Spatial Data and Map Servers
- Advanced Analysis of Geographic Data (socioeconomic variables)
- Cartographic Quality Control, Land Surveys, and Valuation
- Management and Use of Hidrographic Bodies
- Environmental Protection, Land Use Planning, and Assessment and Restructuring

Undergraduate Education

University of Azuay, Cuenca - Ecuador 2011: Bachelors - Information Systems Engineering US Degree equivalence evaluation from WES available upon request

Technologies and Systems

- Databases: Oracle, MySQL, Access
- **Developer Programs**: Oracle JDeveloper 11g, Visual Basic 6.0, Visual Basic .NET, Prolog, Dreamweaver, C++, Oracle Forms, MySQL Workbench, Data Warehouse, NetLogo 4.1.3
- Geographic Information Systems: Arcgis 9.3, Arcgis 10.0, ArcScene 10.0, ENVI, IDRISI SELVA
- Programming Languages: Java, XML, HTML, PHP, ADF, BASIC
- Networking Protocols: DNS, DHCP, HTTP, OSPF, EIGRP, TFTP, Frame Relay, ATM2
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, MAC OS
- Analog and Digital Electronics

Hermano Miguel "La Salle" High School, 2003 - Physics/Math

- Worked as Visual Basic programmer at the "Center of Information Systems Studies" Sponsored by the University of Cambridge, 2003
- Studied in the Physics and Math Specialization Program

Languages: **English** – High level of written and spoken English; **Spanish** – Native

Other Accomplishments

Inline Speed-Skating Champion

- Elite In-line Speed Skater, 2002 2011
 - o Current National Champion in various speed and distance events
 - Represented National Team at the PrePanAmerican Competition in Rosario, Argentina in 2011
 - Represent Provincial and National Teams for International Competitions from 2002 through 2011
 - o Track record-holder for 300-meter sprint, Cuenca, Ecuador
- Skating Coach, Sports Federation of Azuay, 2013 (Cuenca, Ecuador)

• Skating Coach, Hnos. Martinez Club, 2016 (Cuenca, Ecuador)